<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform – Applications</title>
    <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Applications on Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Multicluster</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/multicluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/multicluster/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Verrazzano may be installed in a multicluster environment, consisting of an &lt;em&gt;admin&lt;/em&gt; cluster and optionally, one or more
&lt;em&gt;managed&lt;/em&gt; clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The admin cluster is a central point from which Verrazzano applications in managed clusters can be deployed and monitored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed clusters are registered with an admin cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verrazzano multicluster resources are used to target applications to any cluster in a multicluster Verrazzano environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following diagram shows a high-level overview of how multicluster Verrazzano works. For a more
detailed view, see the diagram &lt;a href=&#34;#detailed-view-of-multicluster-verrazzano&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../docs/images/multicluster/MCConceptsHighLevel.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;admin-cluster&#34;&gt;Admin cluster&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Verrazzano admin cluster is a central management point for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploying and undeploying applications to the managed clusters registered with the admin cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viewing logs and metrics for both Verrazzano components and applications that reside in the managed clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may register one or more managed clusters with the admin cluster by creating a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoManagedCluster&lt;/code&gt;
resource in the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-mc&lt;/code&gt; namespace of an admin cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The admin cluster has a fully functional Verrazzano installation. You can locate applications on the admin
cluster as well as on managed clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;managed-clusters&#34;&gt;Managed clusters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Verrazzano managed cluster has a minimal footprint of Verrazzano, installed using the &lt;code&gt;managed-cluster&lt;/code&gt;
installation profile. A managed cluster has the following additional characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is registered with an admin cluster with a unique name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logs for Verrazzano system components and Verrazzano multicluster applications are sent to
Elasticsearch running on the admin cluster, and are viewable from that cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Verrazzano multicluster Kubernetes resource, created on the admin cluster, will be retrieved and deployed to a
managed cluster if all of the following are true:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The resource is in a namespace governed by a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; has a &lt;code&gt;placement&lt;/code&gt; value that includes this managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The resource itself has a &lt;code&gt;placement&lt;/code&gt; value that includes this managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;verrazzano-multicluster-resources&#34;&gt;Verrazzano multicluster resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano includes several multicluster resource definitions for resources that may be targeted for placement in one
or more clusters: &lt;a href=&#34;../../docs/reference/api/multicluster/multiclusterapplicationconfiguration/&#34;&gt;MultiClusterApplicationConfiguration&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;../../docs/reference/api/multicluster/multiclustercomponent/&#34;&gt;MultiClusterComponent&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;../../docs/reference/api/multicluster/multiclusterconfigmap/&#34;&gt;MultiClusterConfigMap&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href=&#34;../../docs/reference/api/multicluster/multiclustersecret/&#34;&gt;MultiClusterSecret&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each multicluster resource type serves as a wrapper for an underlying resource type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A multicluster resource additionally allows the &lt;code&gt;placement&lt;/code&gt; of the underlying resource to be specified as a list of
names of the clusters in which the resource must be placed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multicluster resources are created in the admin cluster, in a namespace that is part of a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;,
and targeted for &lt;code&gt;placement&lt;/code&gt; in either the local admin cluster or a remote managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A multicluster resource is said to be part of a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; if it is in a namespace that is governed
by that &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;managed-cluster-registration&#34;&gt;Managed cluster registration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A managed cluster may be registered with an admin cluster using a two-step process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a &lt;a href=&#34;../../docs/reference/api/multicluster/verrazzanomanagedcluster/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoManagedCluster&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; resource in the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-mc&lt;/code&gt; namespace of the admin cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Retrieve the Kubernetes manifest file generated in the &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoManagedCluster&lt;/code&gt; resource and apply it on
the managed cluster to complete the registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a managed cluster is registered, the following will happen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After both steps of the registration are complete, the managed cluster begins polling the admin cluster for
&lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; resources and multicluster resources, which specify a &lt;code&gt;placement&lt;/code&gt; in this managed cluster.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; resources placed in this managed cluster are retrieved, and the corresponding namespaces
and security permissions (&lt;code&gt;RoleBindings&lt;/code&gt;) are created in the managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any multicluster resources that are placed in this managed cluster, and are in a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; that is
also placed in this managed cluster, are retrieved, and created or updated on the managed cluster. The
underlying resource represented by the multicluster resource is unwrapped, and created or updated on the managed
cluster. The managed cluster namespace of the multicluster resource and its underlying resource matches
the admin cluster namespace of the multicluster resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the managed cluster connects to the admin cluster, it updates the &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoManagedCluster&lt;/code&gt; resource for this
managed cluster with:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The endpoint URL that the admin cluster should use to scrape Prometheus metrics from the managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The date and time of the most recent successful connection from the managed cluster to the admin cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For &lt;code&gt;MultiClusterApplicationConfigurations&lt;/code&gt; retrieved and unwrapped on a managed cluster, the application logs are
sent to Elasticsearch on the admin cluster, and may be viewed from the Verrazzano-installed Kibana UI on the
admin cluster. Likewise, application metrics will be scraped by the admin cluster and available from
Verrazzano-installed Prometheus on the admin cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;detailed-view-of-multicluster-verrazzano&#34;&gt;Detailed view of multicluster Verrazzano&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This diagram shows a detailed view of how multicluster Verrazzano works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../docs/images/multicluster/MCConcepts.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;try-out-multicluster-verrazzano&#34;&gt;Try out multicluster Verrazzano&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;../../docs/reference/api/&#34;&gt;API Documentation&lt;/a&gt; for the resources described here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To try out multicluster Verrazzano, see the &lt;a href=&#34;../../docs/samples/multicluster/&#34;&gt;Multicluster&lt;/a&gt; examples.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Projects</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/projects/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A Verrazzano project provides a way to group application namespaces that are owned or administered by the same user or
group of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-verrazzanoproject-resource&#34;&gt;The &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; resource&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;../../docs/reference/api/multicluster/verrazzanoproject/&#34;&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt; is created by
a Verrazzano admin user, and specifies the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of namespaces that the project governs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One or more users, groups, or service accounts that will be granted the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-project-admin&lt;/code&gt; role for the
&lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;. Project admins may deploy or delete applications and related resources in the namespaces
in the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One or more users, groups, or service accounts that will be granted the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-project-monitor&lt;/code&gt; role for the
&lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;. Project monitors may view the resources in the namespaces in the project, but not modify
or delete them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of network policies to apply to the namespaces in the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creation of a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; results in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creation of the specified namespaces in the project, if those do not already exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creation of a Kubernetes &lt;code&gt;RoleBindings&lt;/code&gt; in each of the namespaces, to set up the appropriate
permissions for the project admins and project monitors of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The creation of the specified network policies for each of the namespaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Workloads</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/workloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/workloads/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
