<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform – Concepts</title>
    <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Verrazzano and the Open Application Model</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/verrazzanooam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/verrazzanooam/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Open Application Model (OAM) is a runtime-agnostic specification for defining cloud native applications; it allows developers to focus on the application instead of the complexities of a particular runtime infrastructure.  OAM provides the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oam-dev/spec&#34;&gt;specification&lt;/a&gt; for several file formats and rules for a runtime to interpret.  Verrazzano uses OAM to enable the definition of a composite application abstraction and makes OAM constructs available within a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoApplication&lt;/code&gt; YAML file.  Verrazzano provides the flexibility to combine what you want into a multi-cloud enablement. It uses the &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoApplication&lt;/code&gt; as a means to encapsulate a set of components, scopes, and traits, and deploy them on a selected cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OAM&amp;rsquo;s workload concept makes it easy to use many different workload types.  Verrazzano includes specific workload types with special handling to deploy and manage those types, such as WebLogic, Coherence, and Helidon.  OAM&amp;rsquo;s flexibility lets you create a grouping that is managed as a unit, although each component can be scaled or updated independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-oam-work&#34;&gt;How does OAM work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OAM has five core concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workloads - Declarations of the kinds of resources supported by the platform and the OpenAPI schema for that resource.  Most Kubernetes CRDs can be exposed as workloads.  Standard Kubernetes resource types can also be used
(for example, Deployment, Service, Pod, ConfigMap).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Components - Wrap a workload resource&amp;rsquo;s spec data within OAM specific metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application Configurations - Describe a collection of components that comprise an application.  This is also where customization (such as environmental) of each component is done.  Customization is achieved using scopes and traits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scopes - Apply customization to several components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traits - Apply customization to a single component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Verrazzano in a multicluster environment</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/verrazzanomulticluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/verrazzanomulticluster/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Multicluster Verrazzano consists of an &lt;em&gt;admin&lt;/em&gt; Kubernetes cluster and optionally, one or more &lt;em&gt;managed&lt;/em&gt; clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review the following key concepts to understand multicluster Verrazzano:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#admin-kubernetes-cluster&#34;&gt;Admin Kubernetes cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#managed-kubernetes-clusters&#34;&gt;Managed Kubernetes clusters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#the-verrazzanoproject-resource&#34;&gt;The VerrazzanoProject resource&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#verrazzano-multicluster-resources&#34;&gt;Verrazzano multicluster resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#managed-cluster-registration&#34;&gt;Managed cluster registration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#try-out-multicluster-verrazzano&#34;&gt;Try out multicluster Verrazzano&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following diagram shows an overview of how multicluster Verrazzano works:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../images/VerrazzanoMultiCluster.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;admin-kubernetes-cluster&#34;&gt;Admin Kubernetes cluster&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Verrazzano admin cluster is a central management point for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploying and undeploying applications to the managed clusters registered with the admin cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Viewing logs and metrics for both Verrazzano components and applications that reside in the managed clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may register one or more managed clusters with the admin cluster by creating a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoManagedCluster&lt;/code&gt;
resource in the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-mc&lt;/code&gt; namespace of an admin cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The admin cluster has a fully functional Verrazzano installation. You can locate applications on the admin
cluster as well as on managed clusters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;managed-kubernetes-clusters&#34;&gt;Managed Kubernetes clusters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Verrazzano managed cluster has a minimal footprint of Verrazzano, installed using the &lt;code&gt;managed-cluster&lt;/code&gt;
installation profile. A managed cluster has the following additional characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is registered with an admin cluster with a unique name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logs for Verrazzano system components and Verrazzano multicluster applications are sent to
Elasticsearch running on the admin cluster, and viewable from that cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Verrazzano multicluster Kubernetes resource created on the admin cluster will be retrieved and deployed to a
managed cluster if all of the following are true:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The resource is in a namespace governed by a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; is located in this managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The resource itself is located in this managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-verrazzanoproject-resource&#34;&gt;The VerrazzanoProject resource&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;../../reference/api/multicluster/verrazzanoproject&#34; title=&#34;api docs&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; provides a way to group application namespaces that are owned or administered by the
same user or group of users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For multicluster applications to work correctly, a VerrazzanoProject containing the application&amp;rsquo;s namespace must
&lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; be created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; resource is created by a Verrazzano administrative user, and specifies the following:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of namespaces that the project governs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user or group that is designated as the &lt;code&gt;Project Admin&lt;/code&gt; of the VerrazzanoProject. Project admins may deploy
or delete applications and related resources in the namespaces in the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A user or group that is designated as &lt;code&gt;Project Monitor&lt;/code&gt; of the VerrazzanoProject. Project monitors may view
the resources in the namespaces in the project, but not modify or delete them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list of network policies to apply to the namespaces in the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If those namespaces do not already exist, then the creation of a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; results in the creation of the
specified namespaces in the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It also results in the creation of a Kubernetes &lt;code&gt;RoleBinding&lt;/code&gt; in each of the namespaces, to set up the appropriate
permissions for the project admins and project monitors of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verrazzano-multicluster-resources&#34;&gt;Verrazzano multicluster resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano includes several multicluster resource definitions, for resources that may be targeted for placement in one
or more clusters: &lt;a href=&#34;../../reference/api/multicluster/multiclusterapplicationconfiguration&#34; title=&#34;api docs&#34;&gt;MultiClusterApplicationConfiguration&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;../../reference/api/multicluster/multiclustercomponent&#34; title=&#34;api docs&#34;&gt;MultiClusterComponent&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;../../reference/api/multicluster/multiclusterconfigmap&#34; title=&#34;api docs&#34;&gt;MultiClusterConfigMap&lt;/a&gt;,
and &lt;a href=&#34;../../reference/api/multicluster/multiclustersecret&#34; title=&#34;api docs&#34;&gt;MultiClusterSecret&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each multicluster resource type serves as a wrapper for an underlying resource type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A multicluster resource additionally allows the &lt;code&gt;placement&lt;/code&gt; of the underlying resource to be specified as a list of
names of the clusters in which the resource must be placed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multicluster resources are created in the admin cluster, in a namespace that is part of a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;,
and targeted for &lt;code&gt;placement&lt;/code&gt; in either the local admin cluster or a remote managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A multicluster resource is said to be part of a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; if it is in a namespace that is governed
by that &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;managed-cluster-registration&#34;&gt;Managed cluster registration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A managed cluster may be registered with an admin cluster using a two-step process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1:&lt;/strong&gt; Create a &lt;a href=&#34;../../reference/api/multicluster/verrazzanomanagedcluster&#34; title=&#34;api docs&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoManagedCluster&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; resource in the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-mc&lt;/code&gt; namespace of the admin cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2:&lt;/strong&gt; Retrieve the Kubernetes manifest file generated in the &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoManagedCluster&lt;/code&gt; resource and apply it on
the managed cluster to complete the registration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a managed cluster is registered, the following will happen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immediately after the first registration step, the admin cluster begins scraping Prometheus metrics from the newly
registered managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After both steps of the registration are complete, the managed cluster begins polling the admin cluster for
&lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; resources and multicluster resources, which specify a &lt;code&gt;placement&lt;/code&gt; in this managed cluster.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; resources placed in this managed cluster are retrieved, and the corresponding namespaces
and security permissions (&lt;code&gt;RoleBindings&lt;/code&gt;) are created in the managed cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any multicluster resources that are placed in this managed cluster, and are in a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoProject&lt;/code&gt; that is
also placed in this managed cluster, are retrieved, and created or updated on the managed cluster. The
underlying resource represented by the multicluster resource is unwrapped, and created or updated on the managed
cluster. The managed cluster namespace of the multicluster resource and its underlying resource matches
the admin cluster namespace of the multicluster resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For &lt;code&gt;MultiClusterApplicationConfigurations&lt;/code&gt; retrieved and unwrapped on a managed cluster, the application logs are
sent to Elasticsearch on the admin cluster, and may be viewed from the Verrazzano-installed Kibana UI on the
admin cluster. Likewise, application metrics will be scraped by the admin cluster and available from
Verrazzano-installed Prometheus on the admin cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;try-out-multicluster-verrazzano&#34;&gt;Try out multicluster Verrazzano&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, see the &lt;a href=&#34;../../reference/api/&#34;&gt;API Documentation&lt;/a&gt; for the resources described here.
To try out multicluster Verrazzano, see the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/verrazzano/verrazzano/tree/master/examples/multicluster/hello-helidon&#34;&gt;Hello World Helidon multicluster example application&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
