<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform – Concepts</title>
    <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Software Versions</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/versions/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Verrazzano installs a curated set of open source components.  This section lists each open source
component with its version and a brief description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Component&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Version&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;cert-manager&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.13.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automates the management and issuance of TLS certificates.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Coherence Operator&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.1.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Assists with deploying and managing Coherence clusters.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.6.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Provides a distributed, multitenant-capable full-text search engine.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ExternalDNS&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.7.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Synchronizes exposed Kubernetes Services and Ingresses with DNS providers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Filebeat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.8.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Collects container log events and forwards them to Elasticsearch.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Grafana&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.4.4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tool to help you study, analyze, and monitor metrics.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Istio&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1.7.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Service mesh that layers transparently onto existing distributed applications.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Journalbeat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.8.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Collects systemd log events and forwards them to Elasticsearch.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Keycloak&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10.0.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Provides single sign-on with Identity and Access Management.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Kibana&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7.6.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Provides search and data visualization capabilities for data indexed in Elasticsearch.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MySQL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8.0.20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Open source relational database management system used by Keycloak.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NGINX Ingress Controller&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.32.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Traffic management solution for cloud‑native applications in Kubernetes.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Node Exporter&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.18.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Prometheus exporter for hardware and OS metrics.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;OAM Kubernetes Runtime&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0.3.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Plug-in for implementing Open Application Model (OAM) control plane with Kubernetes.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Prometheus&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.13.1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Provides event monitoring and alerting.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Rancher&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2.4.3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Manages multiple Kubernetes clusters.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WebLogic Server Kubernetes Operator&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3.1.0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Assists with deploying and managing WebLogic domains.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Verrazzano and the Open Application Model</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/verrazzanooam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/concepts/verrazzanooam/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;Open Application Model (OAM) is a runtime-agnostic specification for defining cloud native applications; it allows developers to focus on the application instead of the complexities of a particular runtime infrastructure.  OAM provides the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oam-dev/spec&#34;&gt;specification&lt;/a&gt; for several file formats and rules for a runtime to interpret.  Verrazzano uses OAM to enable the definition of a composite application abstraction and makes OAM constructs available within a &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoApplication&lt;/code&gt; YAML file.  Verrazzano provides the flexibility to combine what you want into a multi-cloud enablement. It uses the &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoApplication&lt;/code&gt; as a means to encapsulate a set of components, scopes, and traits, and deploy them on a selected cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OAM&amp;rsquo;s workload concept makes it easy to use many different workload types.  Verrazzano includes specific workload types with special handling to deploy and manage those types, such as WebLogic, Coherence, and Helidon.  OAM&amp;rsquo;s flexibility lets you create a grouping that is managed as a unit, although each component can be scaled or updated independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-oam-work&#34;&gt;How does OAM work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OAM has five core concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workloads - Declarations of the kinds of resources supported by the platform and the OpenAPI schema for that resource.  Most Kubernetes CRDs can be exposed as workloads.  Standard Kubernetes resource types can also be used
(for example, Deployment, Service, Pod, ConfigMap).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Components - Wrap a workload resource&amp;rsquo;s spec data within OAM specific metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application Configurations - Describe a collection of components that comprise an application.  This is also where customization (such as environmental) of each component is done.  Customization is achieved using scopes and traits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scopes - Apply customization to several components.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traits - Apply customization to a single component.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
