<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform – Workloads</title>
    <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/workloads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workloads on Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/workloads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Coherence Workload</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/workloads/coherence/coherence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/workloads/coherence/coherence/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A Verrazzano application can contain any number of Coherence component workloads, where each workload
is a standalone Coherence cluster, independent from other Coherence clusters in the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano uses the standard Coherence operator to provision and manage clusters, as documented
at &lt;a href=&#34;https://oracle.github.io/coherence-operator/docs/latest&#34;&gt;Coherence Operator&lt;/a&gt;.  The Coherence operator
uses a CRD, coherence.oracle.com (Coherence resource), to represent a Coherence cluster.  When a Verrazzano
application with Coherence is provisioned, Verrazzano configures the default logging and
metrics for the Coherence cluster.  Logs are sent to Elasticsearch and metrics to Prometheus.&lt;br&gt;
You can view this telemetry data using the Kibana and Grafana consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;oam-component&#34;&gt;OAM component&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The custom resource YAML file for the Coherence cluster is specified as a VerrazzanoCoherenceWorkload custom resource.
In the following example, everything under the &lt;code&gt;spec:&lt;/code&gt; section is standard Coherence resource YAML that you would typically use
to provision a Coherence cluster.  Including this component reference in your ApplicationConfiguration will result
in a new Coherence cluster being provisioned.  You can have multiple clusters in the same application with no conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apiVersion: core.oam.dev/v1alpha2
kind: Component
metadata:
  name: orders
  namespace: sockshop
spec:
  workload:
    apiVersion: oam.verrazzano.io/v1alpha1
    kind: VerrazzanoCoherenceWorkload
    spec:
      template:
        metadata:
          name: orders-coh
        spec:
          cluster: SockShop
          ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;life-cycle&#34;&gt;Life cycle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Verrazzano, you manage the life cycle of applications using Component and ApplicationConfiguration resources.
Typically, you would modify the Coherence cluster resource to make changes or to do lifecycle operations,
like scale in and scale out.  However, in the Verrazzano environment, the cluster resource is owned by the
Verrazzano application operator and will be reconciled to match the component workload resource.  Therefore,
you need to manage the cluster configuration by modifying the resource, either by &lt;code&gt;kubectl edit&lt;/code&gt; or applying a new YAML file. Verrazzano
will notice that the Component resource changed and will update the Coherence resource as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;provisioning&#34;&gt;Provisioning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you apply the component YAML  file shown previously, Kubernetes will create a &lt;code&gt;component.oam.verrazzano.io&lt;/code&gt; resource, but
the Coherence cluster will not be created until you create the ApplicationConfiguration resource, which references
the Coherence component.  When the application is created, Verrazzano creates a Coherence custom resource for each
cluster, which is subsequently processed by the Coherence operator, resulting in a new cluster.  After a cluster
is created, the Coherence operator will monitor the Coherence resource to reconcile the state of the cluster. You can
add a new Coherence workload to a running application, or remove an existing workload, by modifying
the ApplicationConfiguration resource, and adding or removing the Coherence component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;scaling&#34;&gt;Scaling&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scaling a Coherence cluster is done by modifying the replicas field in the Component resource.  Verrazzano
will modify the Coherence resource replicas field and the cluster will be scaled accordingly.  The following example
configuration shows the &lt;code&gt;replicas&lt;/code&gt; field that specifies the number of pods in the cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apiVersion: core.oam.dev/v1alpha2
kind: Component
metadata:
  name: orders
  namespace: sockshop
spec:
  workload:
    apiVersion: oam.verrazzano.io/v1alpha1
    kind: VerrazzanoCoherenceWorkload
    spec:
      template:
        metadata:
          name: orders-coh
        spec:
          cluster: SockShop
          replicas: 3
          ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; A Coherence cluster provisioned with Verrazzano does not support autoscaling with a Horizontal Pod Autoscaler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;termination&#34;&gt;Termination&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can terminate the Coherence cluster by removing the component from the ApplicationConfiguration or by
deleting the ApplicationConfiguration resource entirely.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;NOTE&lt;/h4&gt;
Do not delete the Coherence component if the application is still using it.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;logging&#34;&gt;Logging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a Coherence cluster is provisioned, Verrazzano configures it to send logs to Elasticsearch.  This is done by
injecting Fluentd sidecar configuration into the Coherence resource. The Coherence operator will create the pod with the
Fluentd sidecar.  This sidecar periodically copies the Coherence logs from &lt;code&gt;/logs&lt;/code&gt; to stdout, enabling the Fluentd DaemonSet
in the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-system&lt;/code&gt; namespace to send the logs to Elasticsearch.  Note that the Fluend sidecar running in the Coherence
pod never communicates with Elasticsearch or any other network endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logs are placed in a per-namespace Elasticsearch index named &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-namespace-&amp;lt;namespace&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;,
for example: &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-namespace-sockshop&lt;/code&gt;.  All logs from Coherence pods in the same namespace will
go into the same index, even for different applications.  This is standard behavior and there is no way to disable or change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each log record has some Coherence and application fields, along with the log message itself.  For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; kubernetes.labels.coherenceCluster        SockShop
 kubernetes.labels.app_oam_dev/name        sockshop-appconf
 kubernetes.labels.app_oam_dev/component   orders
 ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;metrics&#34;&gt;Metrics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano uses Prometheus to scrape metrics from Coherence cluster pods.  Like logging, metrics scraping is also
enabled during provisioning, however, the Coherence resource YAML file must have proper metrics configuration.  For details, see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://oracle.github.io/coherence-operator/docs/latest/#/metrics/020_metrics&#34;&gt;Coherence Metrics&lt;/a&gt;.  In summary,
there are two ways to configure the Coherence metrics endpoint.  Coherence has a default metrics endpoint that you can
enable.  If your application serves metrics from its own endpoint, such as a Helidon application, then do not use the native
Coherence metrics endpoint.  To see the difference, examine the &lt;code&gt;socks-shop&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;bobs-books&lt;/code&gt; examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bobs-books&#34;&gt;Bobs Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/verrazzano/verrazzano/blob/master/examples/bobs-books&#34;&gt;bobs-books&lt;/a&gt; example uses the default
Coherence metrics endpoint, so the configuration must enable this feature, shown in the following metrics section of the
&lt;code&gt;roberts-coherence&lt;/code&gt; component in the YAML file, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/verrazzano/verrazzano/blob/master/examples/bobs-books/bobs-books-comp.yaml&#34;&gt;bobs-books-comp.yaml&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-...&#34; data-lang=&#34;...&#34;&gt;          coherence:
            metrics:
              enabled: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sock-shop&#34;&gt;Sock Shop&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/verrazzano/verrazzano/blob/master/examples/sock-shop&#34;&gt;sock-shop&lt;/a&gt; example, which is a Helidon
application with embedded Coherence, explicitly specifies the metrics port 7001 and doesn&amp;rsquo;t enable Coherence metrics.  Coherence
metrics will still be scraped, but not at the default endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;          ports:
            ...
            - name: metrics
              port: 7001
              serviceMonitor:
                enabled: true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because &lt;code&gt;sock-shop&lt;/code&gt; components are  not using the default Coherence metrics port, you must add a MetricsTrait section
to the ApplicationConfiguration for each component, specifying the metrics port as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;        - trait:
            apiVersion: oam.verrazzano.io/v1alpha1
            kind: MetricsTrait
            metadata:
              name: carts-metrics
            spec:
              port: 7001
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;prometheus-configuration&#34;&gt;Prometheus configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prometheus is configured to scrape targets using the ConfigMaps in the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-system&lt;/code&gt; namespace.  During application deployments,
Verrazzano updates the &lt;code&gt;vmi-system-prometheus-config&lt;/code&gt; ConfigMap and adds targets for the application pods.  Verrazzano also annotates
those pods to match the expected annotations in the ConfigMap. When the application is deleted, Verrazzano removes the targets from
the ConfigMap.  You do not need to manually modify the ConfigMap or annotate the application pods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of the&lt;code&gt;sock-shop&lt;/code&gt; Prometheus ConfigMap section for &lt;code&gt;catalog&lt;/code&gt;.  Notice that pods in the &lt;code&gt;sock-shop&lt;/code&gt; namespace with labels &lt;code&gt;app_oam_dev_name&lt;/code&gt;
and &lt;code&gt;app_oam_dev_component&lt;/code&gt; are targeted.  Prometheus will find those pods and then look at the pod annotations, &lt;code&gt;verrazzano_io/metricsEnabled&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;verrazzano_io/metricsPath&lt;/code&gt;,
and  &lt;code&gt;verrazzano_io/metricsPort&lt;/code&gt; for scrape configuration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- job_name: sockshop-appconf_default_sockshop_catalog
  ...
  kubernetes_sd_configs:
  - role: pod
    namespaces:
      names:
      - sockshop
  relabel_configs:
  - source_labels: [__meta_kubernetes_pod_annotation_verrazzano_io_metricsEnabled,
      __meta_kubernetes_pod_label_app_oam_dev_name, __meta_kubernetes_pod_label_app_oam_dev_component]
  ...  
  - source_labels: [__meta_kubernetes_pod_annotation_verrazzano_io_metricsPath]
  ...
  - source_labels: [__address__, __meta_kubernetes_pod_annotation_verrazzano_io_metricsPort]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is the corresponding &lt;code&gt;catalog&lt;/code&gt; pod labels and annotations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;kind: Pod
metadata:
  labels:
    ...
    app.oam.dev/component: catalog
    app.oam.dev/name: sockshop-appconf
  annotations:
    ...
    verrazzano.io/metricsEnabled: &amp;quot;true&amp;quot;
    verrazzano.io/metricsPath: /metrics
    verrazzano.io/metricsPort: &amp;quot;7001&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;istio-integration&#34;&gt;Istio Integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano ensures that Coherence clusters are not included in an Istio mesh, even if the namespace has the &lt;code&gt;istio-injection: enabled&lt;/code&gt; label.
This is done by adding the &lt;code&gt;sidecar.istio.io/inject: &amp;quot;false&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; annotation to the Coherence resource, resulting in Coherence pods being
created with that label.  However, other application components in the mesh using mutual TLS authentication (mTLS)  may need to communicate with Coherence.  To handle this case,
Verrazzano automatically creates an Istio DestinationRule to disable TLS for the Coherence port.  This policy disables mTLS for port
9000, which happens to be used as a Coherence &lt;code&gt;extend&lt;/code&gt; port for Bob&amp;rsquo;s Books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  trafficPolicy:
    portLevelSettings:
    - port:
        number: 9000
      tls: {}
   ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, port 9000 is the only port where TLS is disabled, so you need to use this as the Coherence &lt;code&gt;extend&lt;/code&gt; port if
other components in the mesh access Coherence over the &lt;code&gt;extend&lt;/code&gt; protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano makes it easy to deploy and observe Coherence clusters in your application, providing seamless integration with other
components in your application running in an Istio mesh.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Helidon Workload</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/workloads/helidon/helidon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/applications/workloads/helidon/helidon/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://helidon.io&#34;&gt;Helidon&lt;/a&gt; is a collection of Java libraries for writing microservices. Helidon provides an open source,
lightweight, fast, reactive, cloud native framework for developing Java microservices. It is available as two frameworks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://helidon.io/docs/latest/#/se/introduction/01_introduction&#34;&gt;Helidon SE&lt;/a&gt; is a compact toolkit that embraces the
latest Java SE features: reactive streams, asynchronous and functional programming, and fluent-style APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://helidon.io/docs/latest/#/mp/introduction/01_introduction&#34;&gt;Helidon MP&lt;/a&gt; implements and supports Eclipse MicroProfile,
a baseline platform definition that leverages Java EE and Jakarta EE technologies for microservices and delivers application
portability across multiple runtimes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helidon is designed and built with container-first philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small footprint, low memory usage and faster startup times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All 3rd party dependencies are stored separately to enable Docker layering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides readiness, liveness and customizable health information for container schedulers like &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Containerized Helidon applications are generally deployed as &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubernetes-api/workload-resources/deployment-v1/&#34;&gt;Deployment&lt;/a&gt; in Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;verrazzano-integration&#34;&gt;Verrazzano integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano supports application definition using &lt;a href=&#34;https://oam.dev/&#34;&gt;Open Application Model (OAM)&lt;/a&gt;. Verrrazzano applications
are composed of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oam-dev/spec/blob/master/3.component.md&#34;&gt;components&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oam-dev/spec/blob/master/7.application_configuration.md&#34;&gt;application configurations&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helidon applications are first class citizen in Verrazzano with specialized Helidon Workload support, for example,
VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload. VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload is supported as part of &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-application-operator&lt;/code&gt; in the
Verrazzano installation and no additional operator setup or installation is required. VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload also supports all
the traits and scopes defined by Verrazzano along with core ones defined by the OAM specification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload is modeled after &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oam-dev/spec/blob/v0.2.1/core/workloads/containerized_workload/containerized_workload.md&#34;&gt;ContainerizedWorkload&lt;/a&gt;,
for example, it is used for long-running workloads in containers. However, VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload closely resembles and directly refers to
Kubernetes &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/kubernetes-api/workload-resources/deployment-v1/&#34;&gt;Deployment&lt;/a&gt; schema. This
enables an easy lift and shift of existing containerized Helidon applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload API
definition and description is available at &lt;a href=&#34;../../../docs/reference/api/oam/workloads/#verrazzanohelidonworkload&#34;&gt;VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;verrazzano-helidon-application-development&#34;&gt;Verrazzano Helidon application development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Verrazzano, you manage the life cycle of applications using Component and ApplicationConfiguration resources. A Verrazzano
application can contain any number of VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload components, where each workload is a standalone
containerized Helidon application, independent of any other in the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following example, everything under the &lt;code&gt;spec:&lt;/code&gt; section is the custom resource YAML file for the containerized Helidon application,
as defined by VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload custom resource. Including this component reference in your ApplicationConfiguration
will result in a new containerized Helidon application being provisioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;apiVersion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;core.oam.dev/v1alpha2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;kind&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;Component&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;metadata&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;hello-helidon-component&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;namespace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;hello-helidon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;workload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;apiVersion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;oam.verrazzano.io/v1alpha1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;kind&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;metadata&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;hello-helidon-workload&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;labels&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;hello-helidon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;deploymentTemplate&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;metadata&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;          &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;hello-helidon-deployment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;podSpec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;          &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;containers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;            &lt;/span&gt;- &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;hello-helidon-container&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;              &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;              &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;../../../docs/samples/application-deployment-guide/&#34;&gt;Application Development Guide&lt;/a&gt; provides end-to-end instructions for
developing and deploying the Verrazzano Helidon application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more Verrazzano Helidon application examples, see &lt;a href=&#34;../../../docs/samples/&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;provisioning&#34;&gt;Provisioning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you apply the previous component YAML file, Kubernetes will create a &lt;code&gt;component.oam.verrazzano.io&lt;/code&gt; resource, but
the containerized Helidon application will not be created until you create the ApplicationConfiguration resource,
which references the VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload component. When the application is created, Verrazzano creates a
Deployment and Service resource for each containerized Helidon application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, you would modify the Deployment and Service resource to make changes or to do lifecycle operations,
like scale in and scale out.  However, in the Verrazzano environment, the containerized Helidon application resource is owned
by the &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-application-operator&lt;/code&gt; and will be reconciled to match the component workload resource. Therefore,
you need to manage the application configuration by modifying the VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload or ApplicationConfiguration resource,
either by &lt;code&gt;kubectl edit&lt;/code&gt; or applying new YAML file. Verrazzano will notice that the component resource change and will update
the Deployment and Service resource as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a new VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload to a running application, or remove an existing workload, by modifying
the ApplicationConfiguration resource and adding or removing the VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scaling&#34;&gt;Scaling&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended way to scale containerized Helidon application replicas is to specify &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oam-dev/spec/blob/v0.2.1/core/traits/manual_scaler_trait.md&#34;&gt;ManualScalerTrait&lt;/a&gt;
with VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload in ApplicationConfiguration. The following example
configuration shows the &lt;code&gt;replicaCount&lt;/code&gt; field that specifies the number of replicas for the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;      &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;components&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;      &lt;/span&gt;- &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;componentName&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;hello-helidon-component&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;traits&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;- &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;trait&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;                      
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;apiVersion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;core.oam.dev/v1alpha2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;kind&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;ManualScalerTrait&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;            &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;spec&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;              &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;replicaCount&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#0000cf;font-weight:bold&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#000&#34;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f8f8f8;text-decoration:underline&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano will modify the Deployment resource &lt;code&gt;replicas&lt;/code&gt; field and the containerized Helidon application replicas will
be scaled accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34; role=&#34;alert&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&#34;alert-heading&#34;&gt;NOTE&lt;/h4&gt;
Make sure the &lt;code&gt;replicas&lt;/code&gt; defined on the VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload component and that &lt;code&gt;replicaCount&lt;/code&gt; defined on ManualScalerTrait
for that component matches, or else the DeploymentController in Kubernetes and OAM runtime in &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-application-operator&lt;/code&gt;
will compete to create a different number of Pods for same containerized Helidon application. To avoid confusion,
we recommend that you specify &lt;code&gt;replicaCount&lt;/code&gt; defined on ManualScalerTrait and leave &lt;code&gt;replicas&lt;/code&gt; undefined on VerrazzanoHelidonWorkload (as it is optional).
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;logging&#34;&gt;Logging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a containerized Helidon application is provisioned on Verrazzano, Verrazzano will configure the default logging
and send logs to Elasticsearch. Logs can be viewed using the Kibana console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logs are placed in a per-namespace Elasticsearch index named &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-namespace-&amp;lt;namespace&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;,
for example: &lt;code&gt;verrazzano-namespace-hello-helidon&lt;/code&gt;.  All logs from containerized Helidon application pods in the same namespace will
go into the same index, even for different applications.  This is standard behavior and there is no way to disable or change it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;metrics&#34;&gt;Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano uses Prometheus to scrape metrics from containerized Helidon application pods. Like logging, metrics scraping is also
enabled during provisioning. Metrics can be viewed using the Grafana console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano lets you to customize configuration information needed to enable metrics using &lt;a href=&#34;../../../docs/reference/api/oam/metricstrait/&#34;&gt;MetricsTrait&lt;/a&gt;
for an application component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingress&#34;&gt;Ingress&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verrazzano lets you to configure traffic routing to a containerized Helidon application, using
&lt;a href=&#34;../../../docs/reference/api/oam/ingresstrait/&#34;&gt;IngressTrait&lt;/a&gt; for an application component.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you have a problem with your Verrazzano Helidon application, there are some basic techniques you
can use to troubleshoot. &lt;a href=&#34;../../../docs/troubleshooting/&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; shows you some simple
things to try when troubleshooting, as well as how to solve common problems you may encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
