<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform – Reference</title>
    <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reference on Verrazzano Enterprise Container Platform</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://verrazzano.io/docs/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/reference/releasenotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/reference/releasenotes/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;v0110&#34;&gt;v0.11.0:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OAM applications are optionally deployed into an Istio service mesh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incremental improvements to user-facing roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix issue with logging when an application has multiple workload types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix metrics configuration in Spring Boot example application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;v0100&#34;&gt;v0.10.0:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Breaking Changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model/binding files removed; now application deployment done exclusively by using Open Application Model (OAM).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax changes for WebLogic and Coherence OAM workloads, now defined using &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoCoherenceWorkload&lt;/code&gt;
and &lt;code&gt;VerrazzanoWebLogicWorkload&lt;/code&gt; types.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By default, application endpoints now use HTTPs - when using magic DNS, certificates are issued by cluster issuer, when using
OCI DNS certificates are issued using Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt, or the end user can provide certificates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Coherence operator to 3.1.3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates for running Verrazzano on Kubernetes 1.19 and 1.20.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RBAC roles and role bindings created at install time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added instance information to status of Verrazzano custom resource; can be used to obtain instance URLs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upgraded Istio to v1.7.3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced log level of Elasticsearch; excessive logging could have resulted in filling up disks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;v090&#34;&gt;v0.9.0:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added platform support for installing Verrazzano on Kind clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log records are indexed from the OAM &lt;code&gt;appconfig&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;component&lt;/code&gt; definitions using the following pattern: &lt;code&gt;namespace-appconfig-component&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All system and curated components are now patchable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More updates to Open Application Model (OAM) support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enable OAM, when you install Verrazzano, specify the following in the Kubernetes manifest file for the Verrazzano custom resource:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#f8f8f8;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;spec:
  oam:
    enabled: &lt;span style=&#34;color:#204a87&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;v080&#34;&gt;v0.8.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for two installation profiles, development (&lt;code&gt;dev&lt;/code&gt;) and production (&lt;code&gt;prod&lt;/code&gt;).  The production profile, which is the default, provides a 3-node Elasticsearch and persistent storage for the Verrazzano Monitoring Instance (VMI). The development profile provides a single node Elasticsearch and no persistent storage for the VMI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The default behavior has been changed to use the system VMI for all monitoring (applications and Verrazzano components).  It is still possible to customize one of the profiles to enable the original, non-shared VMI mode.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial support for the Open Application Model (OAM).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Axios NPM package to v0.21.1 to resolve a security vulnerability in the examples code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;v070&#34;&gt;v.0.7.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to upgrade an existing Verrazzano installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the Verrazzano Console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the structure of the Verrazzano custom resource to allow more configurability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streamlined the secret usage for OCI DNS installations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed bug where the Verrazzano CR &lt;code&gt;Certificate.CA&lt;/code&gt; fields were being ignored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Removed secret used for &lt;code&gt;hello-world&lt;/code&gt;; &lt;code&gt;hello-world-application&lt;/code&gt; image is now public in ghcr so &lt;code&gt;ImagePullSecrets&lt;/code&gt; is no longer needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/verrazzano/verrazzano/issues/339&#34;&gt;issue #339&lt;/a&gt; (PRs &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/verrazzano/verrazzano-operator/pull/208&#34;&gt;#208&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/verrazzano/verrazzano-operator/pull/210&#34;&gt;#210&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;v060&#34;&gt;v0.6.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Features
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In-cluster installer which replaces client-side install scripts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added installation profiles; in this release, there are two: production and development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verrazzano system components now emit JSON structured logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixes
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updated Elasticsearch and Kibana versions (elasticsearch:7.6.1-20201130145440-5c76ab1) and (kibana:7.6.1-20201130145840-7717e73).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Troubleshooting</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/reference/troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/reference/troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h3 id=&#34;known-issues&#34;&gt;Known Issues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;oke-missing-security-list-ingress-rules&#34;&gt;OKE Missing Security List Ingress Rules&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The install scripts perform a check, which attempts access through the ingress ports.  If the check fails, then the install will exit and you will see error messages like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ERROR: Port 443 is NOT accessible on ingress(132.145.66.80)!  Check that security lists include an ingress rule for the node port 31739.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On an OKE install, this may indicate that there is a missing ingress rule or rules.  To verify and fix the issue, do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the ports for the &lt;code&gt;LoadBalancer&lt;/code&gt; services.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run &lt;code&gt;kubectl get services -A&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note the ports for the &lt;code&gt;LoadBalancer&lt;/code&gt; type services.  For example &lt;code&gt;80:31541/TCP,443:31739/TCP&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the security lists in the OCI Console.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;code&gt;Networking/Virtual Cloud Networks&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the related VCN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to the &lt;code&gt;Security Lists&lt;/code&gt; for the VCN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the security list named &lt;code&gt;oke-wkr-...&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the ingress rules for the security list.  There should be one rule for each of the destination ports named in the &lt;code&gt;LoadBalancer&lt;/code&gt; services.  In the above example, the destination ports are &lt;code&gt;31541&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;code&gt;31739&lt;/code&gt;. We would expect the ingress rule for &lt;code&gt;31739&lt;/code&gt; to be missing because it was named in the &lt;code&gt;ERROR&lt;/code&gt; output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a rule is missing, then add it by clicking &lt;code&gt;Add Ingress Rules&lt;/code&gt; and filling in the source CIDR and destination port range (missing port).  Use the existing rules as a guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: API</title>
      <link>https://verrazzano.io/docs/reference/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verrazzano.io/docs/reference/api/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
